PAVEL RUDENKO

Highly motivated IT analyst with 2+ years of professional experience at IT companies. Able to effectively define, describe and translate requirements and priorities according to business needs. Competent in communicating with different stakeholders. Passionate about applying various data analysis tools to achieve better business results.

DETAILS

- Pavel.rudenkoig@gmail.com
- +995522222874
- https://www.linkedin.com/in /pavel-rudenko-2b320b238/

SKILLS

- Python (Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly)
- SQL (Window functions, Subqueries, Joins)
- Math Statistics
- A/B testing
- Visualization in Tableau/PowerBI

LANGUAGES

Russian: Native **English:** Fluent

EDUCATION

05.2022 -10 2022

Karpov.Courses (online School of Data Analysis and Data Science)

2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Engineering Moscow Aviation Institute, Moscow, Russia

WORK HISTORY

May 2022 - November 2022

Data Analyst, Karpov.Courses

Karpov.Courses is online data science school. 8 months practice-oriented program covers most important aspects of Data Analysis.

September 2021 - July 2022

Analyst, Boxberry International, Moscow, Russia

Russian delivery service for international transportation

- Interaction with the business stakeholders: collection, structure and analysis of incoming business requirements;
- Assist in creating informational reports for management based on SQL data;
- Exploratory data analysis using Python;
- Responsible for the full cycle of task implementation: requirements collection, analysis, approval, grooming, release;
- Preparation of instructions for end users;
- Task results presentation for clients

Achievements:

Participation in the launch and development of a new business area (B2B export):

- Prepared and described the requirements for the development of the personal
 account of the online store, which made it possible to simplify and improve the
 customer experience when processing parcels and calculating the cost of sending;
- Developed a diagram (BPMN and flowchart) of business processes, which made it
 possible to build an effective B2B export operation in accordance with the
 requirements of all stakeholders (business, IT);
- Modified the status model for the new export (B2B, B2C)

February 2020 - August 2021

Business Analyst, Sap E-Commerce, MASTERDATA, Moscow, Russia

- Interaction with the business customer: collection, structuring and analysis of incoming business requirements
- User Story development, coordination with the customer (architect, Product Owner)
- Setting development tasks (frontend, backend)
- Development of design requirements
- Participation in the testing of completed tasks and creation of requests for revision

Achievements:

Development of the personal account of the online store (Russian mining company):

- Transformed the "Claims" section in the personal account of the online store by introducing a new UX design for the progress bar and creating step-by-step instructions for the end user, which simplified the process of making a claim by the client;
- Developed and configured the functionality of mass document upload